Register of the New left collection, 1923-2004
Hoover Institution Archives
New Left Collection
1923-2004
69001
Hoover Institution Archives
70 manuscript boxes, 6 oversize boxes, 1 oversize folder, 1 envelope, 1 microfilm, 3 phonorecords (in box 71) (31.0 linear feet)
The New Left Collection largely relates to radical movements for political and social change in the United States during the 1960s and 1970s. It is the largest resource in the archives devoted to this turbulent period in American history. Organized alphabetically by subject file, the collections consists of serial issues and other printed matter, and includes a great deal of ephemera, especially leaflets and flyers. Topics covered in the collection include the movement against the Vietnam War; student radicalism; the civil rights movement and black militancy; revolutionary organizations; the women's liberation movement; and the counter-culture.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1969. An increment was added in 2011.
Related Collection(s)
Radical Right Collection, Hoover Institution Archives
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog Socrates at http://library.stanford.edu/webcat. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in Socrates is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Scope and Content of Collection
The New Left Collection largely relates to radical movements for political and social change in the United States during the 1960s and 1970s. It is the largest resource in the archives devoted to this turbulent period in American history. Organized alphabetically by subject, the collection consists of serial issues and other printed matter, and includes a great deal of ephemera, especially leaflets and flyers. Topics covered in the collection include the movement against the Vietnam War; student radicalism; the civil rights movement and black militancy; revolutionary organizations; the women's liberation movement; and the counter-culture.
There is a special emphasis in the collection on protest movements that emerged on college campuses in the San Francisco Bay Area. There are extensive materials relating to events at Stanford University, the University of California at Berkeley, and San Francisco State University. There is also considerable documentation of the organization, Students for a Democratic Society (SDS), dating from its earliest years through the factional struggles that culminated in a split in SDS in 1969.
The collection was initially developed and curated by Dr. Edward Bacciocco, author of American New Left, 1956-1970 (Hoover Institution Press, 1974). Numerous increments have been added to the collection over the years; many of these incremental materials are described at the end of the finding aid. A number of topics in the register appear more than once, as a general heading or as a subheading, as in the case of Students for a Democratic Society, which appears both as a general subject and under the headings of a number of universities where local groups of SDS were active.
Bacciocco, Edward J.; College students--United States.; Communism--United States.; Conscientious objectors--United States.; Draft--United States.; Radicalism--United States.; Socialism--United States.; Student movements--United States.; Subversive activities--United States.; United States--Social conditions--1960-1980.; Universities and colleges--United States.; Vietnam War, 1961-1975--Protest movements.
- Al Fateh (Palestine Liberation Front), 1971 (Box-folder 1: 1)
- Alinsky Community Development Process, 1968 (Box-folder 1: 2)
- Alternative schools, 1972 (Box-folder 1: 3)
- American Civil Liberties Union, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 4)
- American Committee for Solidarity with the Vietnamese People, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 5)
- American Friends Service Committee, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 1: 6)
- American Indian Movement, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 1: 7)
- American Revolutionary Movement, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 8)
- Amnesty for G.I. Resisters, 1973 (Box-folder 1: 9)
- Anti-draft movement, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 1: 10)
- Anti-drug movement, 1970 (Box-folder 1: 11)
- Anti-war movement, 1965-1973
  - 1965-1969 (Box-folder 1: 12)
  - 1970-1971 (Box-folder 1: 13)
  - 1972 (Box-folder 2: 1)
  - 1973 (Box-folder 2: 2)
- Appalachian Movement Press, 1971 (Box-folder 2: 3)
- April 3rd Movement, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 4)
- April 22, 1972 anti-war marches (Box-folder 2: 5)
- Atlanta Rebellion, 1966 (Box-folder 2: 6)
- Bay Area Poor People's Campaign, 1968 (Box-folder 2: 7)
- Bay Area Radical Education Project, 1970 (Box-folder 2: 8)
- Bay Area Revolutionary Union, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 2: 9)
- Bay Area Spartacist League, 1969 (Box-folder 2: 10)
- Berkeley, 1965-1973
  - General, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - Anti-Draft Union, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 2: 12)
  - April 6th Coalition, 1971 (Box-folder 2: 13)
  - Marijuana Initiative, 1973 (Box-folder 2: 14)
  - October 1968 demonstrations (Box-folder 2: 15)
  - Politics, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - Tenants Strike, February 1970 (Box-folder 3: 2)
- Bibliographies, 1965-1978 (Box-folder 3: 3-5)
- Black movement, 1960-1973
  - Africa and U.S. blacks, 1970 (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - Black Liberation Army, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - Black Muslims, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - Black nationalism, 1950-1971
    - Articles, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 3: 9)
    - Bibliography, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 3 :10)
    - Colonization, 1960-1970 (Box-folder 3 :11)
    - Communist Party, 1969 (Box-folder 3: 12)
    - Cornell University, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 3: 13)
    - Current, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 4: 1)
    - Documentary, 1965 (Box-folder 4: 2)
    - Emigration, 1950 (Box-folder 4: 3)
    - History, 1950-1970 (Box-folder 4: 4)
    - Statistics, 1966-1971 (Box-folder 4: 5)
    - Trade unionism, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 4: 6)
    - Trotskyists and other radical leftists, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 4: 7)
  - Black Panther Party, 1966-1974
    - General, 1966-1974 (Box-folder 4: 8-9)
    - General, 1966-1974 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Algiers, 1971 (Box-folder 5: 2)
    - Urban Crisis Monitor, 1970 (Box-folder 5: 3)
  - Black Politics, 1968 (Box-folder 5: 4)
  - Black power, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 5: 5)
  - Black studies
    - General, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 5: 6)
    - San Francisco State University, 1968 (Box-folder 5: 7)
    - Yale University, 1969 (Box-folder 5: 8)
  - Black United Front at Stanford, 1971 (Box-folder 5: 9)
  - Carmichael, Stokely, 1969 (Box-folder 5: 10)
  - Cuffe, Paul, 1923 (Box-folder 5: 11)
  - Delany, Martin R., 1966-1970 (Box-folder 6: 1)
  - Discrimination and income inequality, 1970 (Box-folder 6: 2)
  - Du Bois, W.E.B., 1968-1970 (Box-folder 6: 3)
  - Galston thesis on Delany, 1969 (Box-folder 6: 4)
  - International Symposium on National Liberation, 1970 (Box-folder 6: 5)
  - Karenga, Ron, 1970 (Box-folder 6: 6)
  - Milton Henry and the Republic of New Africa, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 6: 7)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 6: 8)
  - Newton, Huey P., 1967-1971 (Box-folder 6: 9)
  - Republic of New Africa, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 6: 10)
  - Rustin, Bayard, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 6: 11)
  - Student Non-Violent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), 1963-1970
    - General, 1966-1967 (Box-folder 6: 12)
    - Mississippi and Southern States, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 6: 13)
    - Mississippi and Southern States, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 7: 1-2)
  - Miscellany, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 7: 3)
- Blackguards and Guardettes, 1970 (Box-folder 7: 4)
- Boston Draft Resistance Group newsletters, 1968-69 (Box-folder 7: 5)
- Brown Berets, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 7: 6)
- Cambridge Movement for a Democratic Society, 1965 (Box-folder 7: 7)
- Cambridge Peace and Freedom Party, 1974 (Box-folder 7: 8)
- Campus Crusade for Christ, 1971 (Box-folder 7: 9)
- Canadian Party of Labour, 1971 (Box-folder 7: 10)
- Castro, Fidel, 1965 (Box-folder 7: 11)
- Catholic Peace Fellowship of Northern California, 1969 (Box-folder 7: 12)
- Catonsville 9 and Harrisburg 8, 1971 (Box-folder 8: 1)
- Central Committee for Conscientious Objectors, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 8: 2)
- Chicago Conspiracy Trial, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 8: 3)
- Chicago convention, 1968 (Box-folder 8: 4)
- Chicano movement, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 8: 5)
- China, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 8: 6)
- Christian World Liberation Front, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 7)
- Clergy and Laymen Concerned About Vietnam, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 8: 8)
- Clippings, 1970 (Box-folder 8: 9-13)
- Clippings, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 9: 1-9)
- Clippings, 1971 (Box-folder 10: 1-11)
- Clippings, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 11: 1-13)
- Clippings and documents, 1967-1972
  - New Left General, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 11: 14)
  - Democratic National Convention, 1972 (Box-folder 11: 15)
  - Republican National Convention, 1972 (Box-folder 11: 16)
- Collector's Exchange Newsletter, 1972 (Box-folder 11: 17)
- Columbia University, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 11: 18)
- Committee to Defend the Rights of Pfc. Howard Petrick, 1967 (Box-folder 12: 1)
- Committee to Support the Revolution in Peru, 1991 (Box-folder 12: 2)
- Communes, Drug related (Entitas), 1971-1972 (Box-folder 12: 3)
- Communiqué for New Politics and Left-out News, Berkeley, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 12: 4)
- Communist Party of the United States (CPUSA), 1964-1971 (Box-folder 12: 5)
- Conservative societies, 1963-1965 (Box-folder 12: 6)
- Counter-culture, 1960-1972
  - General, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 12: 7-11)
  - General, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 13: 1-3)
  - Clippings on hippies, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 4)
  - Digger Papers, 1967 (Box-folder 13: 5-6)
  - Family Dog, 1969 (Box-folder 13: 7)
  - File of Michael Bowen, 1965-1969
    - Clippings, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 14: 1)
    - Magazine articles, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 14: 2)
    - Personal correspondence and papers, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 14: 3)
  - Newspapers, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 14: 4-5)
  - Newspapers, 1967 (Box-folder 15: 1-2)
  - Photographs, 1967 (Box-folder 15: 3-6)
  - "Siddhartha" by Nina Graboi, 1965 (Box-folder 15: 7)
- Counterdraft, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 15: 8)
- Cuba, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 15: 9)
- Cultural revolution, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 15: 10)
- CU News, Berkeley, 1969 (Box-folder 15: 11)
- Davenport, Tim, 1987-1988 (Box-folder 15: 12)
- Davis, Angela, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 16: 1)
- Delano grape strike, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 16: 2)
- Dellums, Ron, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 16: 3)
- Democratic Popular Front for the Liberation of Palestine, 1970 (Box-folder 16: 4)
- Democratic Socialists of America (formerly the Democratic Socialist Organizing Committee), 1978-1989 (Box-folder 16: 5)
- Dig This Now, 1969 (Box-folder 16: 6)
- Dope, 1972 (Box-folder 16: 7)
- Draft resistance, 1967-1971
  - General, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 16: 8)
  - Flyers and leaflets, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 16: 9)
  - Pamphlets, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 16: 10)
  - Serial issues, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 16: 11)
- Ecology, 1970-1973 (Box-folder 16: 12)
- Environment, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 16: 13)
- Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1967 (Box-folder 17: 1)
- Franklin, Bruce. "The Lumpenproletariat and the Revolutionary Youth Movement," undated, 1970 (Box-folder 17: 2)
- Freedom schools, 1965 (Box-folder 17: 3)
- Gay Liberation Front, 1970 (Box-folder 17: 4)
- General Electric Strike, 1969 (Box-folder 17: 5)
- General Motors Strike, 1970 (Box-folder 17: 6)
- Georgia Communist League and the October League, 1972 (Box-folder 17: 7)
- G.I. Anti-war movement, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 17: 8)
- Grape boycott, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 17: 9)
- Greenpeace, 1978-1988 (Box-folder 17: 10)
- Grito del Norte, 1970 (Box-folder 17: 11)
- Guerrilla warfare, 1970 (Box-folder 17: 12)
- Haight-Ashbury materials, 1967 (Box-folder 17: 13)
- Harrisburg Conspiracy Trial, 1972 (Box-folder 17: 14)
- Harvard University, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 17: 15)
- Hayden, Tom. "Student Social Action,", 1962 (Box-folder 17: 16)
- High school movement, 1965-1972 (Box-folder 18: 1-3)
- Hoover Institution, 1971-73 (Box-folder 18: 4)
- Imperialism, 1969 (Box-folder 18: 5)
- Independent Socialist, 1966-1968 (Box-folder 18: 6)
- Independent Socialists, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 18: 7)
- Independent Socialist Club, 1969 (Box-folder 18: 8)
- Indochina Solidarity Committee, 1972 (Box-folder 18: 9)
- Insurgent Sociologist, 1973 (Box-folder 18: 10)
- Integration in the South, 1960-1971 (Box-folder 18: 11)
- International Bolshevik Tendency, 1991 (Box-folder 18: 12)
- International Industrial Conference, 1969 (Box-folder 18: 13)
- International Liberation Front, North American Division, 1968 (Box-folder 18: 14)
- International Liberation School, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 18: 15)
- International Network Against New State Repression, 1989 (Box-folder 18: 16)
- International socialist and leftist publications, 1967-1992
  - Miscellaneous, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 19: 1)
  - Pamphlets, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 19: 2)
  - Serial issues, 1967-1992 (Box-folder 19: 3-8)
- Iranian Students Association, Berkleley, 1973 (Box-folder 20: 1)
- Iranian Students Association in Northern California, 1973 (Box-folder 20: 2)
- Israeli Socialist Organization, 1968 (Box-folder 20: 3)
- Jesus movement, 1971-1973+ (Box-folder 20: 4)
- Jewish Peace Fellowship of the Fellowship of Reconciliation, 1968 (Box-folder 20: 5)
- John Reed Co-op Book Center, 1987 (Box-folder 20: 6)
- Johnny Appleseed Patriotic Publications, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 20: 7)
- Key List Mailing (SNCC), 1964-1965 (Box-folder 20: 8)
- Labor movements, 1966-1973 (Box-folder 20: 9)
- Laney College, Oakland, California, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 20: 10)
- Lawton, Gary, 1975 (Box-folder 20: 11)
- League for Industrial Democracy, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 20: 12)
- League of Revolutionary Black Workers, 1970 (Box-folder 21: 1)
- Liberal Religious Youth, 1973 (Box-folder 21: 2)
- Liberalism, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 21: 3)
- Liberation, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 21: 4)
- Liberation Party, 1973 (Box-folder 21: 5)
- Liberation Support Movement, 1971 (Box-folder 21: 6)
- Libertarianism (anarchism), 1969 (Box-folder 21: 7)
- Life with Lyndon in the Great Society, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 21: 8)
- Literature lists, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 21: 9)
- Los Angeles Board of Police Commissioners, 1974 (Box-folder 21: 10)
- Los Siete de la Raza, 1971 (Box-folder 21: 11)
- Magee, Ruchell, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 21: 12)
- Marxism, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 21: 13)
- Marxist Bulletin, 1971 (Box-folder 21: 14)
- May Day Collective, 1971 (Box-folder 21: 15)
- McCarthy, Eugene. Campaign, 1968 (Box-folder 22: 1)
- McGovern, George. Campaign, 1972 (Box-folder 22: 2)
- Measure, 1971 (Box-folder 22: 3)
- Merritt College, Oakland, California, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 22: 4)
- Middle East, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 22: 5)
- Militant Labor Forum, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 22: 6)
- Military-industrial complex, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 22: 7)
- Miscellaneous, 1958-1966 (Box-folder 22: 8-9)
- Miscellaneous, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 23: 1-5)
- Miscellaneous, 1969-1979 (Box-folder 24: 1-7)
- Mississippi Freedom Democratic Party, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 25: 1)
- Movement organizations, 1971 (Box-folder 25: 2)
- Movement security, 1969-1971 (Box-folder 25: 3)
- National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), 1964-1965 (Box-folder 25: 4)
- National Lawyers' Guild, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 25: 5)
- National Peace Action Coalition, 1970-1972
  - General, 1970-1972 (Box-folder 25: 6)
  - National convention, 1972 (Box-folder 25: 7)
- National Student Association and the CIA, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 25: 8)
- National Student Labor Action Project, 1969 (Box-folder 25: 9)
- National Welfare Rights Organization, 1970 (Box-folder 25: 10)
- New American Movement, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 25: 11)
- New American Views, 1980 (Box-folder 25: 12)
- New Mobilization Committee to End the War in Vietnam, 1970 (Box-folder 25: 13)
- New Party, 1970 (Box-folder 25: 14)
- New Patriot (published by Johnny Appleseed Patriotic Publications), 1970 (Box-folder 25: 15)
- Newsreel, 1970 (Box-folder 25: 16)
- Nicaragua, 1978 (Box-folder 25: 17)
- Non-violence, 1971 (Box-folder 25: 18)
- November Moratorium, 1969 (Box-folder 25: 20)
- Oakland, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 26: 1)
- October Moratorium, 1969 (Box-folder 26: 2)
- Oil, Chemical and Atomic Workers strike, 1969 (Box-folder 26: 3)
- "Our Generation Kits", 1965-1969 (Box-folder 26: 4-9)
- Outside the Net, 1973 (Box-folder 26: 10)
- Pacific and Asian Affairs Council, 1972 (Box-folder 26: 11)
- Palo Alto, 1970 (Box-folder 26: 12)
- Palo Alto Tenants Union, 1970 (Box-folder 26: 13)
- Panther 21, 1970 (Box-folder 26: 14)
- Peace and Freedom News, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 26: 15)
- Peace and Freedom Organizer, 1967 (Box-folder 27: 1)
- Peace and Freedom Party, 1967-1990 (Box-folder 27: 2-3)
- Peace and Freedom Review, 1968 (Box-folder 27: 4)
- Peace movement, 1970 (Box-folder 27: 5)
- Peninsula New Left activities, 1970 (Box-folder 27: 6)
- Peninsula New Party, 1971 (Box-folder 27: 7)
- People's Coalition for Peace and Justice, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 27: 8)
- People's Park, Berkeley, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 26: 9)
- People's Party, 1973 (Box-folder 27: 10)
- People's Yellow Pages, 1972 (Box-folder 27: 11)
- Police Defense Movement, 1971 (Box-folder 27: 12)
- Presidential campaigns and the New Left, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 27: 13)
- Presidio 27, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 27: 14)
- Prison movement, 1972 (Box-folder 27: 15)
- Prison rebellions, 1971 (Box-folder 27: 16)
- Progressive Labor Party, 1963-1973
  - General, 1963-1969 (Box-folder 27: 17)
  - General, 1967-1973 (Box-folder 28: 1-2)
  - Berkeley Club, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 28: 3)
- Puerto Rican Revolutionary Party, 1970 (Box-folder 28: 4)
- Quattrone, David. "Giving Truth to the Summer's Lie", 1965 (Box-folder 28: 5)
- Racism, 1963-1971 (Box-folder 28: 6-8)
- Racism, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 29: 1-2)
- Radical and/or revolutionary speakers, 1970 (Box-folder 29: 3)
- Radical Education Project, 1963-1968 (Box-folder 29: 4)
- Radicalism in the United States, 1954-1975
  - Antiwar, 1965-1967 (Box-folder 29: 5)
  - Beat movement, 1957-1969 (Box-folder 29: 6)
  - Berkeley, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 29: 7)
  - Berkeley, 1964-1969 (Box-folder 30: 1)
  - Black power, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 30: 2)
  - Black radical community newspapers, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 30: 3)
  - British New Left, 1956-1962 (Box-folder 30: 4)
  - Chessman, Caryl, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 30: 5)
  - Civil rights movement, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 30: 6)
  - Clippings, 1968-1971 (Box-folder 30: 7-11)
  - Columbia University, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 30: 12)
  - Columbia Spectator, 1968 (Box-folder 31: 1)
  - Community organizing, 1964-1968 (Box-folder 31: 2-3)
  - Council of Federated Organizations (Mississipi Summer Project), 1964-1965 (Box-folder 31: 4-5)
  - Criticisms of New Left, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 32: 1)
  - Critics, 1958-1970 (Box-folder 32: 2)
  - Cuba, 1961-1970 (Box-folder 32: 3-4)
  - Du Bois Clubs, 1965-1968 (Box-folder 32: 5)
  - Free Student, 1965 (Box-folder 32: 6)
  - High school movement, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 32: 7)
  - House Un-American Activities Committee, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 32: 8)
  - Key articles, 1965-1975 (Box-folder 32: 9)
  - Liberalism, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 32: 10)
  - Miscellaneous, 1960-1968 (Box-folder 33: 1-4)
  - Miscellaneous, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 34: 1-5)
  - National Student Association and Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee, 1960-1962 (Box-folder 34: 6)
  - New Left, 1964-1971 (Box-folder 35: 1)
  - The New Left in America: Reform to Revolution, 1967-1972 (Box-folder 35: 2-12)
  - New Left Notes, 1966-1969 (Box-folder 36: 1)
  - New politics convention, 1967 (Box-folder 36: 2)
  - Peace movement, 1959-1962 (Box-folder 36: 3)
  - People's Bicentennial Commission, 1970-1976 (Box-folder 36: 4)
  - Period of transition, 1960-1963 (Box-folder 36: 5)
  - Professors, 1968 (Box-folder 36: 6)
  - Radical America, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 36: 7)
  - Recapitulation, 1962-1969 (Box-folder 36: 8)
  - Resistance, 1967-1968 (Box-folder 36: 9)
  - Revolutionary culture and Yippies, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 36: 10)
  - San Francisco State University, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 37: 1)
  - Serial issues, 1965-1969 (Box-folder 37: 2-5)
  - Student Nonviolent Coordinating Committee (SNCC), 1954-1972
    - General, 1962-1970 (Box-folder 38: 1-3)
    - Black power and Black Panthers, 1967-1969 (Box-folder 38: 4)
    - Important material, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 38: 5)
    - Key articles, 1954-1971 (Box-folder 38: 6)
    - March on Washington, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 38: 7)
  - Students, 1955-1960 (Box-folder 39: 1)
  - Students for a Democratic Society (SDS), 1960-1971
    - General, 1960-1969 (Box-folder 39: 2-5)
    - 1969 Convention (Box-folder 39: 6)
    - Bulletins, 1964-1965 (Box-folder 39: 7)
    - Economic Research and Action Project (ERAP), 1960-1965 (Box-folder 39: 8)
    - Key articles, 1965-1971 (Box-folder 40: 1)
    - Position papers, 1964-1969 (Box-folder 40: 2-3)
    - Universities and student politics, 1965-1970 (Box-folder 40: 4)
    - Violence, 1967-1970 (Box-folder 40: 5)
    - Young Socialist Alliance, 1969 (Box-folder 40: 6)
- Radicals in electoral politics, 1973 (Box-folder 40: 7)
- Radicals in the professions, 1968-1972
  - General, 1969-1972 (Box-folder 40: 8)
  - Computer People for Peace, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 40: 9)
  - Serial issues, 1968-1973 (Box-folder 40: 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 40: 10)
    - Miscellaneous, 1968-1972 (Box-folder 41: 1)
    - No More Teachers' Dirty Looks, 1971-1973 (Box-folder 41: 2)
    - The Radical Therapist, 1970-1971 (Box-folder 41: 3)
    - The Teacher Paper, 1972-1973 (Box-folder 41: 4)
    - Vocations for Social Change, 1971 (Box-folder 41: 5)
- Red Balloon Collective (New York State University, Stony Brook), 1972 (Box-folder 41: 6)
- Red Guard, Peninsula and San Francisco, 1969 (Box-folder 41: 7)
- Red Papers (Revolutionary Union), 1969-1972 (Box-folder 41: 8)
- Religious movements, 1972 (Box-folder 42: 1)
- Repression, 1971 (Box-folder 42: 2)
- Republican National Convention, Miami, 1972 (Box-folder 42: 3-5)
- Research debate, 1969 (Box-folder 42: 6)
- Resistance, 1967-1971 (Box-folder 42: 7)
- Revolutonary People's Communications Network (RPCN), 1972 (Box-folder 42: 8)
- Revolutionary Union, 1971-1972 (Box-folder 42: 9)
- Right On (Berkeley), 1972 (Box-folder 43: 1)
- Right-wing bumper stickers, 1962-1968 (Box-folder 43: 2)
- San Diego Coalition, 1972 (Box-folder 43: 3)
- San Francisco State University, 1968-1970
  - General, 1969-1970 (Box-folder 43: 4-6)
  - Academic Senate, 1969 (Box-folder 43: 7)
  - American Federation of Teachers, 1969 (Box-folder 43: 8)
  - Associated Students, 1969 (Box-folder 43: 9)
  - Black Student Union, 1969 (Box-folder 43: 10)
  - California State, 1969 (Box-folder 43: 11)
  - Campus Communications Center, 1969
  - Coalition of Concerned Faculty, 1969 (Box-folder 44: 1)
  - Committee for an Academic Environment, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 44: 2)
  - Daily Gator, 1968-1970 (Box-folder 44: 3-5)
  - Disciplinary procedures, 1969 (Box-folder 44: 6)
  - Faculty issues, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 44: 7)
  - Footnotes, 1969 (Box-folder 44: 8)
  - Independent Socialists, 1969 (Box-folder 44: 9)
  - Leaflets, 1969 (Box-folder 44: 10)
  - Newspaper clippings, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 45: 1)
  - On the record..., 1968-1969 (Box-folder 45: 2)
  - Open Process, 1968-1969 (Box-folder 45: 3)
  - Phoenix, 1969 (Box-folder 45: 4-5)
  - President's Office, 1969 (Box-folder 45: 6)